# Santiago Cervan Front end Developer

<u>santicervan@live.com</u> +54 3517380506 <u>Córdoba - Argentina</u>.

Portafolio LinkedIn GitLab GitHub

I am a Front End web developer with strong skills in designing and developing responsive web pages, focusing on optimization and speed. I also have experience in implementing Back End to Front End functionalities. My approach is user-centered, creating user-friendly and intuitive interfaces that enhance the user experience.

I am self-reliant in researching and selecting suitable libraries and frameworks, quickly adapting to the required technologies by the company. I am organized in task management and utilize the Scrum methodology for effective communication and meeting deadlines.

# **TECH SKILLS**

√ JavaScript	√ Typescript	✓ React	✓ NextJs	√ React Native	✓ Redux	
✓ Node.js	✓ HTML	✓ CSS	✓ Express	✓ Postgres	√ Sequelize	✓ Figma

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Leadership, adaptability, empathy, public speaking, open-mindedness, planning and organization, creativity, decision-making, teamwork, effective communication.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Voike Music – Front-end Developer (Part-time)

october 2023 - present

- · Layout and design optimization.
- Performance and SEO improvements.
- Efficient Git Flow management for effective version control.
- Integration with Backend Endpoints.
- Front-end functionality development.
- Support for the company's legacy projects.

### **Global Think Technology –** Front-end Developer (Temporary)

october 2023 - december 2023

- Integration with Backend Endpoints.
- Front-end functionality development.
- Efficient Git Flow management for effective version control.
- Support for the company's legacy projects.

#### Noa Experience – Front-end Developer (Full-time)

october 2022 - october 2023

- Layout and design optimization, enhancing user experience, and reducing load times.
- Efficient Git Flow management for effective version control.
- Initiating new projects.
- Integration with Backend Endpoints.
- Front-end functionality development.
- Support for the company's legacy projects.

#### PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

Senior technician in programming - Teclab

august 2023 - present

Tertiary education

Full Stack Web Developer - Henry Bootcamp

may 2022 - september 2022

Intensive bootcamp of over 800 hours of coding

march 2022 - may 2022

Introduction to Programming – Argentina Programa

Introductory programming course

# **LANGUAGES**

• Native Spanish speaker.

English (C1 Advanced).

English Certificate 68/100 (C1 Advanced) - EFSET

september 2022

Link to certificate: **EFSET Certificate** 

# **PROJECTS**

Voike october 2023 – december 2023

Voike Music, Bogotá, Colombia.

Refactoring old code.

- Applying SEO strategies to improve positioning.
- Enhancing performance by refactoring code and optimizing multimedia resources.
- Web development using NextJs with JavaScript and Tailwind for the Front-end.

Omuni October 2023 – december 2023

Global Think Technology, Córdoba, Argentina.

Implementing new functionalities for a communication system.

Front-end development using ReactJs with TypeScript, and Styled Components for designs.

**Electa** january 2022 – october 2023

Noa Experience, Bogotá, Colombia.

- Initiated the project, managed the repository, implemented Git Flow, designed, developed, and implemented
  functionalities for a social media web application targeting followers of political candidates in Colombia.
   Features include registration (Google or Facebook), login, news panel, multimedia, surveys, referrals, profile
  editing, challenges, etc.
- Developed the app using Next.js with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS.

lunctus december 2022 – february 2023

Noa Experience, Bogotá, Colombia.

- Initiated the project, managed the repository, implemented Git Flow, designed, developed, and implemented functionalities for a system to track law projects and chamber members. Features include date-based searches, filters, sorting, login, administrator role, project creation, editing, and deletion.
- Developed the app using Next.js with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS.

Weeki october 2022 – december 2022

Noa Experience, Bogotá, Colombia.

- Designed, developed, and implemented functionalities for a web application focused on apartment rentals in Bogotá, Colombia. Features include date-based searches, reservations, online payments, etc.
- Developed the app using Next.js with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS.